# **Atul Jayant Jairam**

Software Development Engineer

**Phone:** (514) 814-0465 **Address:** Montreal, QC

**LinkedIn:** https://www.linkedin.com/in/AtulJairam465/

Email: atuljayant465@gmail.com

Enthusiastic IT professional with 4 years of experience in the Health Care IT Industry. Skilled in Databases and various Web Technology Domains like Angular, React, and NodeJS. I have completed my intensive studies in Programming and Web Technologies from Institut superieur d'informatique to enhance my skills in this field. I am organized, hardworking and versatile with excellent problem-solving skills. I am a philomath and adaptive to any recent technology that would challenge and help me explore my limits.

#### EXPERIENCE

## eClinicalWorks, India

Aug 2017 - Feb 2021

#### Software Specialist

- Worked on Health Care Medical Record application which was used by providers based in the US.
- worked on Technologies: ReactJS, NodeJS.
- Coordinated with the client to understand the requirements and changes in the project.
- Used AzureDevOps for code versioning of the project. Followed Agile Scrum Methodology for the management of the Projects. Worked on Visual Studio Enterprise for code integration
- Worked on Azure services for hosting the development database. Also
- Created the database schemas for the table and the data. Performed and created manual test cases. Worked on technologies: MSSQL, MySQL, Azure.
- Analyzed the application to seek out any issues and performed regression tests. Worked on JIRA, AzureDevOps, and Github for version control.
- Performed maintenance on Apache servers.

#### EDUCATION

# Institut superieur d'informatique – Montreal, Quebec

 $march\ 2021$  - present

Programming and Web Technologies, Attestation of College Studies

## **Bharati Vidyapeeth College of Engineering - INDIA**

July 2013 - July 2017

Bachelor of Engineering (Information Technology)

7.3 GPA

#### SKILLS

## Languages:

Javascript, TypeScript, Java, Android, C++, PHP, Golang

Tools:

VS Code, Android Studio, DockerCompose, JIRA, GIT, PostMan, PhpStorm, IntelliJ ommunity edition

Frameworks/Technologies:

Angular, React, Node.js, HTML, CSS, BOOTSTRAP, Flutter, MySQL, MSSQL, GitHub, AZURE, Docker.

## **PROJECTS**

#### The weather App

Nov 2021 - Dec 2021

#### https://github.com/WhiteFang465/The\_Weather\_App

This application was developed to show the weather of all the cities in the world. It can take any language and show the output for that city. The application was created using Restful/REST API, NodeJS, and ReactJs.

AnimeWorld Feb 2022-mar 2022

## https://github.com/WhiteFang465/Anime-World

A Mobile application that gives you the list of all the animes. Search for your favourite anime and get the description about it. You can save and get information about your favorite animes. the technology for this project is Android, Room Database, and was developed using Android Studio.

May 2022 - Jun 2022

## https://github.com/WhiteFang465/MasterMind\_Game

A game that tests your memory and recollection skills. This game involves a computer that generates a random 4-digit number and the role of the player is to guess that code. You have unlimited tries and as a plus point, you get hints from the computer on how close you are to guessing the code. This hint will disappear on your next guess so you need to remember them and get it right.

## OTHER EXPERIENCE

## **Reception Worker (Condensing Team)**

Oct 2021 - present

## Lufa Farms, Montreal

- Receiving and putting products away.
- Checking the inventory for issues.
- Condensing the inventory.
- Ensure the freezers are always clean.